oroton.com.au 2009-06-19

# Privacy Policy

### OROTON'S TERMS OF USE AND DISCLAIMER

This website is owned by, and content is published OrotonGroup (Australia) Pty Limited A.C.N. 000 704 129 trading as Oroton ("Publisher"). You must not access, browse or use this website unless you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions set out below. If you do not agree to these terms and conditions, you must not use this website. For an explanation of the practices and policies of Publisher relating to the collection, use, and storage of information of users of this website, users should refer to the Privacy Policy and Disclosure Statement of Publisher on this website. 

The information contained on this website is intended for general information only and should not be considered to be complete or definitive. Information on this website may contain technical inaccuracies or typographical errors. Publisher accepts no responsibility regarding the accuracy of information that is provided by Publisher on this website and use of such information is at your own risk. Publisher reserves the right to make changes at any time, without notice, to any element of the website. All content and functionality on this website is provided "as is" and without warranties of any kind by Publisher, express or implied. This website contains links to sites maintained by other organisations, and Publisher does not take any responsibility for the content or functionality of those sites. You should take appropriate action to ensure that your access to, and use of this website and other sites is protected against, and free from viruses (including macro viruses), worms, trojan horses and other harmful and destructive material.

Publisher does not want to receive confidential or proprietary information from you through this website. All information or material sent to Publisher will be deemed not to be confidential. You grant Publisher an unrestricted irrevocable licence to use, reproduce, display, perform, modify, transmit and distribute that information or material, for any purpose.

Publisher will not be liable to any party for any direct, indirect, special or other consequential damages arising out of any use of this website, or any other hyperlinked website, and including, but without limitation, loss of profits, interruption of business, loss of data on your information handling system or otherwise, even if Publisher has been expressly advised of the possibility of such damages. Publisher provides no representations or warranties, express or implied, including any implied warranties of fitness for a particular purpose, merchantability or otherwise in relation to any information provided by Publisher on this website.

All statutory or implied terms, conditions or warranties concerning the quality or condition of this website or any information, service, material, advice or recommendation supplied by Publisher to you through this website is limited to the fullest extent permitted by law. If Publisher breaches any term, condition or warranty which is implied by law and cannot lawfully be excluded, the liability of Publisher for a breach of the applicable term, condition or warranty is limited to, at the election of Publisher:  
(i) the resupply of the relevant advice, service, recommendation or information; or  
(ii) the payment to you of the cost of having the relevant advice, service, recommendation or information supplied again

Except to the extent that liability may not lawfully be excluded, Publisher will not be under any liability to you (or any of your officers, agents or employees) for any loss of profit or anticipated profit, loss of data, loss of use, damage to goodwill and loss due to delay, or other direct or indirect loss or damage (including without limitation consequential loss or damage,) however caused (including without limitation due to breach of contract, negligence and/or breach of statute) which may be suffered or incurred or which may arise from or in connection with your use of this website or your use of or reliance upon any of the information, services and/or materials contained in it or provided by it to you or negligence or breach by the Publisher of Publisher obligations under these Terms of Use. Publisher does not warrant that any of the functions contained in the website or your access to the website will be uninterrupted or error-free, or that any notifications (such as may be selected in the investor relations section of the website), will be made in a timely manner, or at all. The information contained in this website is derived from sources believed to be true and accurate. However, the content may include errors and changes or events may occur which cause the information to be inaccurate or out of date. For various reasons substantial delays may occur before particular information on the website is updated. Accordingly, Publisher does not warrant the reliability, accuracy, currency or completeness of that information and any reliance by you upon that information is at your sole risk. You should satisfy yourself as to the currency and accuracy of any information provided through this website. You must indemnify Publisher and hold Publisher harmless against all loss, actions, proceedings, costs, expenses (including legal fees), claims and damages arising from any breach by you of these Terms of Use, your access and/or use of the website or reliance on its contents or information received through it by yourself or any person accessing any content through your website.

(i) to monitor or improve the quality and standard of service provided to you or other consumers by Publisher and any entitles related to Publisher, (collectively called "Authorised Disclosees");  
(ii) to provide marketing information to you about products and services of any one or more of the Authorised Disclosees; and  
(iii) arrange for delivery of goods of any one or more Authorised Disclosees to you. 

Publisher may at any time revise these terms and conditions by updating this website. By using this website you agree to be bound by all revisions and you should therefore periodically visit this page to determine the then current terms which govern your relationship with Publisher.

The materials displayed on this website, including without limitation all information, text, graphics, names, logos, trademarks, design, software and advertisements ("Content") are protected by copyright, trade mark and other intellectual property laws unless expressly indicated otherwise on the website. You may access and display these pages on a computer or a monitor only for your personal and non-commercial use. All other use (including without limitation reproduction on any other website) of any part of this website is prohibited without express written permission of Publisher. You must not use this website in any manner or for any purpose which is unlawful or which violates the rights of any owner of any content. Nothing contained in this website should be construed as a licence or right of use of any trademark displayed on the website without the express written permission of the owner of the trademark.

This agreement is governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of New South Wales. You irrevocably and unconditionally submit to the non-exclusive jurisdiction of the courts of New South Wales. If any provision of this agreement is found to be invalid or unenforceable by a court of law, such invalidity or unenforceability will not affect the remainder of this agreement, which will continue in full force and effect. 

© OrotonGroup (Australia) Pty Limited A.C.N. 000 704 129. All rights reserved. No part of this site may be reproduced in any manner without express written permission from Publisher.

### OROTON PRIVACY POLICY & DISCLOSURE STATEMENT

### Application

OrotonGroup (Australia) Limited A.C.N. 000 704 129 trading as Oroton (collectively referred to as "Publisher", "we", "our", or "us") is subject to the National Privacy Principles in the Privacy Act 1988. This Privacy Policy and Disclosure Statement explains how Publisher collects and protects the privacy of personal information about you collected by the Publisher or provided by you to Publisher via our website or from other sources. 

This Privacy Policy and Disclosure Statement does not apply in relation to acts and practices of Publisher which relate directly to the employee records of present and former employees of Publisher.

### Collection Of Your Personal Information

You agree and consent that we may collect personal information from you when you subscribe to one of our OrotonGroup websites or instore mailing lists, and from the people we do business with (“business clients”) such as our suppliers and contractors.  Normally, the type of personal information collected includes your name, email and postal addresses, home and business telephone numbers, age and gender.  We do not generally collect sensitive personal information.

Our policy is to only collect personal information that we need for a particular purpose and use it for that purpose.  Except as permitted or required by law, including as reasonably expected by the individual, OrotonGroup does not collect, use or disclose personal information without your consent. 

You agree and consent that OrotonGroup may collect personal information about you from a third party source.  OrotonGroup will take reasonable steps to contact you to and make you aware of the purposes for which the issuer has collected your personal information which has been obtained from a third party source.

You must not provide personal information to OrotonGroup about another person, unless that person has authorised OrotonGroup, through you, to collect, use and disclose personal information about that person for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

DISCLOSURE STATEMENT

Publisher collects personal information for some or all of the following purposes:  

(i) to monitor or improve the quality and standard of service provided to you or other consumers by Publisher and any entities related to Publisher, (collectively called "Authorised Disclosees");  
(ii) to provide marketing information to you about products and services of any one or more of the Authorised Disclosees; and  
(iii) arrange for delivery of products of any one or more Authorised Disclosee to you. 

If you do not provide any information requested, Publisher or one or more of the Authorised Disclosees may not be able to either provide you with information about Oroton products or to fulfil one or more other purposes of collection of your personal information.

Publisher may collect personal information about you from a third party source. Publisher will take reasonable steps to contact you and make you aware of the purposes for which Publisher has collected your personal information which has been obtained from a third party source.

### Use Or Disclosure Of Your Personal Information

You agree and consent that we may use personal information to manage our relationship with you and business clients and properly conduct our business.  Specifically, you agree and consent that we may use your personal information in order to:

·                     communicate information on our products or services and to notify our customers about existing or new OrotonGroup product offerings, sales or special promotions from time to time;

·                     help you decide which of our products would best suit your requirements;

·                     Conduct market research by collating and analysing information in order to develop product ranges and identify opportunities to provide our customers with further service and benefits. 

If at any time you no longer wish to be notified about new OrotonGroup products or services or promotions, you should contact the Privacy Officer (see details below), and OrotonGroup will delete your personal information from our system. 

You agree and consent that OrotonGroup’s use of your personal information may involve sharing your personal information with and amongst the companies within the OrotonGroup.  Where information is disclosed to a related body corporate, that company is bound by the original purpose for which the information was collected. 

OrotonGroup does not sell, rent, trade, give or share personal information to or with third parties.  However, you agree and consent that we may disclose your personal information to third parties to whom OrotonGroup contracts out specialised functions (including without limitation such as printing companies for the purpose of printing OrotonGroup’s promotional material).  If OrotonGroup does disclose your personal information to these third party contractors under outsourcing or contracting arrangements, OrotonGroup takes steps to ensure that those contractors comply with the National Privacy Principles when they handle your personal information, and are authorised only to use your personal information in order to provide the services or to perform the functions required by OrotonGroup. 

Otherwise, OrotonGroup only uses or discloses personal information as authorised or required by law.

###  

### Personal Information About Other People

You must not provide personal information to Publisher about another person, unless that person has authorised Publisher, through you, to collect, use and disclose personal information about that person for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy and Disclosure Statement.   

### Sharing Information

Publisher may disclose personal information to Authorised Disclosees upon the basis that any Authorised Disclosee may only collect, use or disclose the information for the purpose for which that information was originally collected by Publisher. 

### Access To Personal Information

Publisher will, on request, provide you with access to personal information held by Publisher about you, subject to any limitations or exceptions in the Privacy Act.  
Publisher will deal with requests for access within a reasonable time. You must pay Publisher for reasonable costs incurred by Publisher in providing you with access.  
If Publisher refuses to provide you with access to personal information about you, Publisher will provide you with reasons for the refusal, in accordance with the requirements of the Privacy Act. 

### Consent

We understand that when you visit our website you may not wish to become a member. We respect that and have provided you the option to not sign up as a member and to drop out at any time you no longer wish to be a member of the website. 

### Up-to-Date Information

Publisher will take reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is up-to-date when collected or used by Publisher. If any personal information held by Publisher about you is incorrect, you should contact Publisher immediately, so that Publisher can take reasonable steps to correct incorrect information about you. 

### Security of Personal Information

Publisher protects your personal information from misuse and unauthorised disclosure.  
Personal information about you may be stored in hard copy or electronically in data information storage systems of Publisher.  
Publisher maintains physical security, as well as network and computer security over paper and electronic data information storage systems. 

### Children and young people

The website is accessible to people of all ages. However, we are mindful that some customers who register as members may be under the age of 18. In the interests of their personal safety, we urge children to check with their parents before entering personal information on any website and ask parents to discuss these issues with their children.  
The Publisher will also ensure that appropriate disclosures are made at the time of collection of other information from minors, and will only collect this information where it is appropriate to do so. Information collected will only be used for appropriate purposes. 

### Foreign Countries

Publisher will not transfer your personal information to foreign countries without your express or implied consent. 

### Contacts

You may gain access to your personal information, make a complaint about breach of your privacy rights, or make enquiries about collection or use of your personal information by contacting the Publisher Privacy Officer: 

Publisher will respond to your query or complaint in a reasonable time.

© OrotonGroup (Australia) Limited A.C.N. 000 704 129. All rights reserved. No part of this site may be reproduced in any manner without express written permission of Publisher.
